# **Nick Wehner**

(317) 903-7214 nrwehner@gmail.com

## **Service Oriented, Creative Problem-Solver**

Well-balanced and experienced business professional with a broad skillset focused on service excellence. Both a strong desire and proven record of quickly learning complex concepts and information including electric power operations, physical power trading, various software platforms, data analysis and reporting, and online training methods. Thrives in a balanced work environment with a variety of task types (analytical, creative, routine) and both independent and team-based work.

- Excellent attention to detail
- Strong drive to take initiative
- Keen eye for problem-solving and solution development
- Excellent communication skills

- Loyal and dependable team member
- Reporting and data mining experience
- Quick independent learner
- Creative analytical thinker

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Eleven Fifty Academy

Jan 2020 - Present

**Student - .Net Framework Coding Bootcamp** – Fishers, IN

Sabbatical Mar 2019 – Jan 2020

#### MISO (Midcontinent Independent System Operator)

Nov 2018 – Mar 2019

**Quality Process Analyst** – Carmel, IN

Coordination and Implementation of cross-departmental process improvement initiatives.

#### **ACES (Alliance for Cooperative Energy Services)**

Feb 2010 - Nov 2018

Process Control Analyst (Sep 2015 – Nov 2018) – Carmel, IN

Senior contributor to a team of trading control and process improvement analysts. Utilized balanced skillset by performing a wide variety of functions for the team and the company. Served as a key contact for solving complex business process problems.

- Developed, improved, and repaired business processes
- Utilized Microsoft Office (Visual Basic) products to design work automation solutions
- Designed risk system (Allegro) customizations (including SQL coding) to improve efficiency and offer improved work solutions
- Compiled, analyzed, and distributed trade data statistics reports (ad-hoc requests and periodic)
- Analyzed details of company processes by performing control testing for internal audits
- Wrote data queries (Microsoft Access) and supported use of queries company-wide
- Facilitated a team of individuals focused on process improvement initiatives for the energy trading function of the company

### Hourly Trader (Aug 2014 – Sep 2015) – Carmel, IN

Team member and shift participant on a desk of hourly traders covering a 24/7 shift managing the power supply needs of various clients. Monitored detailed system information to independently make quick, high-impact decisions.

- Communicated with energy market counterparties to trade (buying and selling) real-time energy bilaterally on behalf of clients
- Communicated with power plant operators and regional power system operators to facilitate appropriate plant dispatch
- Monitored pricing, weather, and resource statuses in real-time, responding accordingly
- Responded to various system disturbances that impacted clients (plant outages, transmission line outages, directives from system operators, etc.)
- Performed various market research and reporting tasks on behalf of the team

## **Trading Control Analyst** (Feb 2013 – Aug 2014) - Raleigh, NC

Contributor to a team of trading control analysts serving the needs of clients and internal staff. Balanced daily data analysis work with long-term projects and customer service requests of clients and internal staff.

- Performed daily and long-term power trade verification, analysis, and capture in company risk system (Allegro), including reconciliation with counterparty confirmation letters
- Performed daily upload, maintenance, and problem-solving of client data warehouse
- Reviewed trade data queries (Access) on a daily basis, investigating discrepancies
- Assisted with writing and updating trade data queries
- Responded to internal and client requests, including support of risk system use and trade data accuracy

### Training Specialist (Feb 2010 – Sep 2012) – Carmel, IN

Collaborated with my supervisor to develop new product offering to our clients as well as our internal staff: a library of online training courses teaching energy risk management, power system operations, and NERC Standards topics. Quickly learned new complex information, converting learning into detailed training material.

- Built online courses by designing and selecting graphics, writing and recording transcripts, and developing and synching animations
- Administered NERC CE Provider Program (continuing education for NERC-certified System
  Operators) and company Learning Management System (LMS) internally and externally,
  including submitting completion of training hours to NERC for certificate credit, responding to
  user questions and issues, and system reporting
- Participant in Reliability Compliance service including administrative assistance, NERC standards research, and training support for clients.

#### THE LITTLE STAR CENTER

Sep 2012 – Feb 2013

#### ABA Therapist - Carmel, IN

Worked one-on-one with two teenage students on the Autism Spectrum at a supervised behavioral modification center based on Applied Behavioral Analysis (ABA) theories.

• Implemented behavioral, social, and educational interventions, "discrete trial" teaching, life skills coaching, and guided children through community outings and group-based activities

#### **EDUCATION**

HOPE COLLEGE – Holland, MI
Bachelor of Arts: Psychology Major
WESTERN THEOLOGICAL SEMINARY – Holland, MI
Master of Divinity – completed 1st year

Sep 2004 – May 2008

Minors: Business Management and Philosophy

Sep 2008 – May 2009